scrcpy 2.4 <https://github.com/Genymobile/scrcpy>
Usage: E:\Dev\Work\zbbvrui\src-tauri\scrcpy\scrcpy.exe [options]

Options:

    --always-on-top
        Make scrcpy window always on top (above other windows).

    --audio-bit-rate=value
        Encode the audio at the given bit rate, expressed in bits/s. Unit
        suffixes are supported: 'K' (x1000) and 'M' (x1000000).
        Default is 128K (128000).

    --audio-buffer=ms
        Configure the audio buffering delay (in milliseconds).
        Lower values decrease the latency, but increase the likelyhood of buffer
        underrun (causing audio glitches).
        Default is 50.

    --audio-codec=name
        Select an audio codec (opus, aac, flac or raw).
        Default is opus.

    --audio-codec-options=key[:type]=value[,...]
        Set a list of comma-separated key:type=value options for the device
        audio encoder.
        The possible values for 'type' are 'int' (default), 'long', 'float' and
        'string'.
        The list of possible codec options is available in the Android
        documentation:
        <https://d.android.com/reference/android/media/MediaFormat>

    --audio-encoder=name
        Use a specific MediaCodec audio encoder (depending on the codec provided
        by --audio-codec).
        The available encoders can be listed by --list-encoders.

    --audio-source=source
        Select the audio source (output or mic).
        Default is output.

    --audio-output-buffer=ms
        Configure the size of the SDL audio output buffer (in milliseconds).
        If you get "robotic" audio playback, you should test with a higher value
        (10). Do not change this setting otherwise.
        Default is 5.

    -b, --video-bit-rate=value
        Encode the video at the given bit rate, expressed in bits/s. Unit
        suffixes are supported: 'K' (x1000) and 'M' (x1000000).
        Default is 8M (8000000).

    --camera-ar=ar
        Select the camera size by its aspect ratio (+/- 10%).
        Possible values are "sensor" (use the camera sensor aspect ratio),
        "<num>:<den>" (e.g. "4:3") or "<value>" (e.g. "1.6").

    --camera-id=id
        Specify the device camera id to mirror.
        The available camera ids can be listed by:
            scrcpy --list-cameras

    --camera-facing=facing
        Select the device camera by its facing direction.
        Possible values are "front", "back" and "external".

    --camera-high-speed
        Enable high-speed camera capture mode.
        This mode is restricted to specific resolutions and frame rates, listed
        by --list-camera-sizes.

    --camera-size=<width>x<height>
        Specify an explicit camera capture size.

    --camera-fps=value
        Specify the camera capture frame rate.
        If not specified, Android's default frame rate (30 fps) is used.

    --crop=width:height:x:y
        Crop the device screen on the server.
        The values are expressed in the device natural orientation (typically,
        portrait for a phone, landscape for a tablet). Any --max-size value is
        computed on the cropped size.

    -d, --select-usb
        Use USB device (if there is exactly one, like adb -d).
        Also see -e (--select-tcpip).

    --disable-screensaver
        Disable screensaver while scrcpy is running.

    --display-buffer=ms
        Add a buffering delay (in milliseconds) before displaying. This
        increases latency to compensate for jitter.
        Default is 0 (no buffering).

    --display-id=id
        Specify the device display id to mirror.
        The available display ids can be listed by:
            scrcpy --list-displays
        Default is 0.

    --display-orientation=value
        Set the initial display orientation.
        Possible values are 0, 90, 180, 270, flip0, flip90, flip180 and flip270.
        The number represents the clockwise rotation in degrees; the "flip"
        keyword applies a horizontal flip before the rotation.
        Default is 0.

    -e, --select-tcpip
        Use TCP/IP device (if there is exactly one, like adb -e).
        Also see -d (--select-usb).

    -f, --fullscreen
        Start in fullscreen.

    --force-adb-forward
        Do not attempt to use "adb reverse" to connect to the device.

    --forward-all-clicks
        By default, right-click triggers BACK (or POWER on) and middle-click
        triggers HOME. This option disables these shortcuts and forwards the
        clicks to the device instead.

    -h, --help
        Print this help.

    -K
        Same as --keyboard=uhid.

    --keyboard=mode
        Select how to send keyboard inputs to the device.
        Possible values are "disabled", "sdk", "uhid" and "aoa".
        "disabled" does not send keyboard inputs to the device.
        "sdk" uses the Android system API to deliver keyboard events to
        applications.
        "uhid" simulates a physical HID keyboard using the Linux UHID kernel
        module on the device.
        "aoa" simulates a physical keyboard using the AOAv2 protocol. It may
        only work over USB.
        For "uhid" and "aoa", the keyboard layout must be configured (once and
        for all) on the device, via Settings -> System -> Languages and input ->
        Physical keyboard. This settings page can be started directly using the
        shortcut MOD+k (except in OTG mode) or by executing: `adb shell am start
        -a android.settings.HARD_KEYBOARD_SETTINGS`.
        This option is only available when a HID keyboard is enabled (or a
        physical keyboard is connected).
        Also see --mouse.

    --kill-adb-on-close
        Kill adb when scrcpy terminates.

    --legacy-paste
        Inject computer clipboard text as a sequence of key events on Ctrl+v
        (like MOD+Shift+v).
        This is a workaround for some devices not behaving as expected when
        setting the device clipboard programmatically.

    --list-cameras
        List device cameras.

    --list-camera-sizes
        List the valid camera capture sizes.

    --list-displays
        List device displays.

    --list-encoders
        List video and audio encoders available on the device.

    --lock-video-orientation[=value]
        Lock capture video orientation to value.
        Possible values are "unlocked", "initial" (locked to the initial
        orientation), 0, 90, 180 and 270. The values represent the clockwise
        rotation from the natural device orientation, in degrees.
        Default is "unlocked".
        Passing the option without argument is equivalent to passing "initial".

    -m, --max-size=value
        Limit both the width and height of the video to value. The other
        dimension is computed so that the device aspect-ratio is preserved.
        Default is 0 (unlimited).

    -M
        Same as --mouse=uhid.

    --max-fps=value
        Limit the frame rate of screen capture (officially supported since
        Android 10, but may work on earlier versions).

    --mouse=mode
        Select how to send mouse inputs to the device.
        Possible values are "disabled", "sdk", "uhid" and "aoa".
        "disabled" does not send mouse inputs to the device.
        "sdk" uses the Android system API to deliver mouse eventsto
        applications.
        "uhid" simulates a physical HID mouse using the Linux UHID kernel module
        on the device.
        "aoa" simulates a physical mouse using the AOAv2 protocol. It may only
        work over USB.
        In "uhid" and "aoa" modes, the computer mouse is captured to control the
        device directly (relative mouse mode).
        LAlt, LSuper or RSuper toggle the capture mode, to give control of the
        mouse back to the computer.
        Also see --keyboard.

    -n, --no-control
        Disable device control (mirror the device in read-only).

    -N, --no-playback
        Disable video and audio playback on the computer (equivalent to
        --no-video-playback --no-audio-playback).

    --no-audio
        Disable audio forwarding.

    --no-audio-playback
        Disable audio playback on the computer.

    --no-cleanup
        By default, scrcpy removes the server binary from the device and
        restores the device state (show touches, stay awake and power mode) on
        exit.
        This option disables this cleanup.

    --no-clipboard-autosync
        By default, scrcpy automatically synchronizes the computer clipboard to
        the device clipboard before injecting Ctrl+v, and the device clipboard
        to the computer clipboard whenever it changes.
        This option disables this automatic synchronization.

    --no-downsize-on-error
        By default, on MediaCodec error, scrcpy automatically tries again with a
        lower definition.
        This option disables this behavior.

    --no-key-repeat
        Do not forward repeated key events when a key is held down.

    --no-mipmaps
        If the renderer is OpenGL 3.0+ or OpenGL ES 2.0+, then mipmaps are
        automatically generated to improve downscaling quality. This option
        disables the generation of mipmaps.

    --no-power-on
        Do not power on the device on start.

    --no-video
        Disable video forwarding.

    --no-video-playback
        Disable video playback on the computer.

    --orientation=value
        Same as --display-orientation=value --record-orientation=value.

    --otg
        Run in OTG mode: simulate physical keyboard and mouse, as if the
        computer keyboard and mouse were plugged directly to the device via an
        OTG cable.
        In this mode, adb (USB debugging) is not necessary, and mirroring is
        disabled.
        LAlt, LSuper or RSuper toggle the mouse capture mode, to give control of
        the mouse back to the computer.
        Keyboard and mouse may be disabled separately using--keyboard=disabled
        and --mouse=disabled.
        It may only work over USB.
        See --keyboard and --mouse.

    -p, --port=port[:port]
        Set the TCP port (range) used by the client to listen.
        Default is 27183:27199.

    --pause-on-exit[=mode]
        Configure pause on exit. Possible values are "true" (always pause on
        exit), "false" (never pause on exit) and "if-error" (pause only if an
        error occured).
        This is useful to prevent the terminal window from automatically
        closing, so that error messages can be read.
        Default is "false".
        Passing the option without argument is equivalent to passing "true".

    --power-off-on-close
        Turn the device screen off when closing scrcpy.

    --prefer-text
        Inject alpha characters and space as text events instead of key events.
        This avoids issues when combining multiple keys to enter a special
        character, but breaks the expected behavior of alpha keys in games
        (typically WASD).

    --print-fps
        Start FPS counter, to print framerate logs to the console. It can be
        started or stopped at any time with MOD+i.

    --push-target=path
        Set the target directory for pushing files to the device by drag & drop.
        It is passed as is to "adb push".
        Default is "/sdcard/Download/".

    -r, --record=file.mp4
        Record screen to file.
        The format is determined by the --record-format option if set, or by the
        file extension.

    --raw-key-events
        Inject key events for all input keys, and ignore text events.

    --record-format=format
        Force recording format (mp4, mkv, m4a, mka, opus, aac, flac or wav).

    --record-orientation=value
        Set the record orientation.
        Possible values are 0, 90, 180 and 270. The number represents the
        clockwise rotation in degrees.
        Default is 0.

    --render-driver=name
        Request SDL to use the given render driver (this is just a hint).
        Supported names are currently "direct3d", "opengl", "opengles2",
        "opengles", "metal" and "software".
        <https://wiki.libsdl.org/SDL_HINT_RENDER_DRIVER>

    --require-audio
        By default, scrcpy mirrors only the video when audio capture fails on
        the device. This option makes scrcpy fail if audio is enabled but does
        not work.

    -s, --serial=serial
        The device serial number. Mandatory only if several devices are
        connected to adb.

    -S, --turn-screen-off
        Turn the device screen off immediately.

    --shortcut-mod=key[+...][,...]
        Specify the modifiers to use for scrcpy shortcuts.
        Possible keys are "lctrl", "rctrl", "lalt", "ralt", "lsuper" and
        "rsuper".
        A shortcut can consist in several keys, separated by '+'. Several
        shortcuts can be specified, separated by ','.
        For example, to use either LCtrl+LAlt or LSuper for scrcpy shortcuts,
        pass "lctrl+lalt,lsuper".
        Default is "lalt,lsuper" (left-Alt or left-Super).

    -t, --show-touches
        Enable "show touches" on start, restore the initial value on exit.
        It only shows physical touches (not clicks from scrcpy).

    --tcpip[=ip[:port]]
        Configure and reconnect the device over TCP/IP.
        If a destination address is provided, then scrcpy connects to this
        address before starting. The device must listen on the given TCP port
        (default is 5555).
        If no destination address is provided, then scrcpy attempts to find the
        IP address of the current device (typically connected over USB), enables
        TCP/IP mode, then connects to this address before starting.

    --time-limit=seconds
        Set the maximum mirroring time, in seconds.

    --tunnel-host=ip
        Set the IP address of the adb tunnel to reach the scrcpy server. This
        option automatically enables --force-adb-forward.
        Default is localhost.

    --tunnel-port=port
        Set the TCP port of the adb tunnel to reach the scrcpy server. This
        option automatically enables --force-adb-forward.
        Default is 0 (not forced): the local port used for establishing the
        tunnel will be used.

    -v, --version
        Print the version of scrcpy.

    -V, --verbosity=value
        Set the log level (verbose, debug, info, warn or error).
        Default is info.

    --v4l2-sink=/dev/videoN
        Output to v4l2loopback device.
        It requires to lock the video orientation (see
        --lock-video-orientation).
        This feature is only available on Linux.

    --v4l2-buffer=ms
        Add a buffering delay (in milliseconds) before pushing frames. This
        increases latency to compensate for jitter.
        This option is similar to --display-buffer, but specific to V4L2 sink.
        Default is 0 (no buffering).
        This option is only available on Linux.

    --video-codec=name
        Select a video codec (h264, h265 or av1).
        Default is h264.

    --video-codec-options=key[:type]=value[,...]
        Set a list of comma-separated key:type=value options for the device
        video encoder.
        The possible values for 'type' are 'int' (default), 'long', 'float' and
        'string'.
        The list of possible codec options is available in the Android
        documentation:
        <https://d.android.com/reference/android/media/MediaFormat>

    --video-encoder=name
        Use a specific MediaCodec video encoder (depending on the codec provided
        by --video-codec).
        The available encoders can be listed by --list-encoders.

    --video-source=source
        Select the video source (display or camera).
        Camera mirroring requires Android 12+.
        Default is display.

    -w, --stay-awake
        Keep the device on while scrcpy is running, when the device is plugged
        in.

    --window-borderless
        Disable window decorations (display borderless window).

    --window-title=text
        Set a custom window title.

    --window-x=value
        Set the initial window horizontal position.
        Default is "auto".

    --window-y=value
        Set the initial window vertical position.
        Default is "auto".

    --window-width=value
        Set the initial window width.
        Default is 0 (automatic).

    --window-height=value
        Set the initial window height.
        Default is 0 (automatic).

Shortcuts:

    In the following list, MOD is the shortcut modifier. By default, it's (left)
    Alt or (left) Super, but it can be configured by --shortcut-mod (see above).

    MOD+f
        Switch fullscreen mode

    MOD+Left
        Rotate display left

    MOD+Right
        Rotate display right

    MOD+Shift+Left
    MOD+Shift+Right
        Flip display horizontally

    MOD+Shift+Up
    MOD+Shift+Down
        Flip display vertically

    MOD+g
        Resize window to 1:1 (pixel-perfect)

    MOD+w
    Double-click on black borders
        Resize window to remove black borders

    MOD+h
    Middle-click
        Click on HOME

    MOD+b
    MOD+Backspace
    Right-click (when screen is on)
        Click on BACK

    MOD+s
    4th-click
        Click on APP_SWITCH

    MOD+m
        Click on MENU

    MOD+Up
        Click on VOLUME_UP

    MOD+Down
        Click on VOLUME_DOWN

    MOD+p
        Click on POWER (turn screen on/off)

    Right-click (when screen is off)
        Power on

    MOD+o
        Turn device screen off (keep mirroring)

    MOD+Shift+o
        Turn device screen on

    MOD+r
        Rotate device screen

    MOD+n
    5th-click
        Expand notification panel

    MOD+Shift+n
        Collapse notification panel

    MOD+c
        Copy to clipboard (inject COPY keycode, Android >= 7 only)

    MOD+x
        Cut to clipboard (inject CUT keycode, Android >= 7 only)

    MOD+v
        Copy computer clipboard to device, then paste (inject PASTE keycode,
        Android >= 7 only)

    MOD+Shift+v
        Inject computer clipboard text as a sequence of key events

    MOD+k
        Open keyboard settings on the device (for HID keyboard only)

    MOD+i
        Enable/disable FPS counter (print frames/second in logs)

    Ctrl+click-and-move
        Pinch-to-zoom and rotate from the center of the screen

    Shift+click-and-move
        Tilt (slide vertically with two fingers)

    Drag & drop APK file
        Install APK from computer

    Drag & drop non-APK file
        Push file to device (see --push-target)

Environment variables:

    ADB
        Path to adb executable

    ANDROID_SERIAL
        Device serial to use if no selector (-s, -d, -e or --tcpip=<addr>) is
        specified

    SCRCPY_ICON_PATH
        Path to the program icon

    SCRCPY_SERVER_PATH
        Path to the server binary

Exit status:

      0  Normal program termination
      1  Start failure
      2  Device disconnected while running
